Joseph Kelly

Digital Designer

j4seph@gmail.com 07858938743 Leeds, UK

Portfolio www.j4seph.co.uk

About Me

I'm passionate and driven to make a long lasting career in digital design. I'm fascinated by well designed websites, applications and experiences, and want to be involved in the process of creating them for customers. I've been a professional designer for 4 years now and have learnt to love designing creative, beautiful, and accessible customer facing experiences, which is why I want to submerge myself into digital design.

I'm hardworking, focused, quick at learning and adapting to new situations, plus endlessly self-improving.

Professional Digital Design and UI/UX Experience

I would definitely recommend visiting my portfolio for a more in-depth view at the projects I have worked on

Courierinsurance.org **Head Designer** 2017 - Present

Co-founded a lead generation website with the purpose of connecting delivery drivers in need of insurance with insurance brokers.

I designed and created the functioning brand and website from the ground up. Appealing to the target audience and guiding them through a customer journey, ending with the customer submitting a form to be contacted.

My role includes:

- Branding
- Wireframing
- Developing Customer Journeys/User FlowsLow and High Fidelity Prototypes
- Dynamic/Responsive DesignUsability Testing
- User Résearch (Heat Mapping and Analytics)
- AB Testing
- Accessibility Testing
- Copywriting

From the launch of the website, it has been consistently profitable, each month generating over a 100% return on investment on ad spend.

Hermes Local - 2021 hermeslocal.com

For the delivery company, Hermes, I designed a landing page promoting their new zero-emissions. local delivery service. This design can be found by following the link above.

This project was a lot of fun, I enjoyed breathing life into their design systems and branding. I was able to incorporate the company's core branding along with their ethos into a fresh design.

J and S Foods - 2021 iandsfoods.net

J and S Foods is a fresh food wholesaler that has been trading in Leeds since 1977. They required a full website redesign. I achieved the goal of giving them a much needed breath of fresh air to their online presence. Building out the various pages of this website gave me great satisfaction and it was an excellent learning experience. I think it has had a great impact on my skills and has taken my web designs to the next level.

Skills/Tools

- Adobe Creative Suite (XD, Illustrator, Photoshop)
- Wireframing and Whiteboarding
- HTML, CSS, Javascript, React JS
- Wordpress
- Google and Facebook Analytics

Past Experience

Milestone Insurance

Marketing Manager: 2017 - Present

Salesman: 2014 - 2017

My years at Milestone Insurance have given me a lot of valuable experience, which I will take with me when I move on to a new company.

During my time as the Marketing Manager, I carried out the following tasks:

- Customer/User Research
- Responsive Landing Page Designs
- Ad Creative Designs
- Copywriting
- Google and Facebook Analytics
- Google and Facebook Ads

Through this role, I learnt to understand customer profiles. This allowed me to cater to the experience that they would expect, guiding them on a journey from initial interaction to purchase.

Before this, I was a salesman at the company, with the responsibility of speaking to customers, explaining the product and service that we can provide, followed by closing the sale. From the time that I spent in this role, I gained a lot of confidence within myself and my abilities. I improved my verbal and written communication skills and learnt to motivate myself through stressful situations, whilst still achieving to hit time-driven goals.

Education

The Complete Web Developer in 2021, Zero to Mastery (Udemy):

- HTML
- · CSS
- UI/UX Design
- Responsive Design
- Javascript
- React JS

The Creative Javascript Course (Dev Ed)

Edexcel Level 3 NVQ Diploma in Marketing (QCF)

Edexcel BTEC Level 3 Certificate in Principles of Marketing (QCF)

Parklane College, Leeds A Level: Media, Film, Photography, Maths